A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Cultural Interests, Series E FA314
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Organizations and Parks
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Transfer to Virgin Islands National Park, 1956-1957 (Box 86, Folder 800)
    Public relations arrangements for ceremonies on land transfer; invitations; guests; Laurance S. Rockefeller address.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Transfer to Virgin Islands National Park, 1956-1957 (Box 86, Folder 0800A)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Menors Ferry, 1949-1952 (Box 86, Folder 801)
    Restoration of Snake River crossing by Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memos on Future Plans, 1952 (Box 86, Folder 802)
    Outline of plans for area; new buildings.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Minutes, 1957-1961 (Box 86, Folder 803)
    Arrangements for meetings; special projects.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Chase Loan, 1955, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 804)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller gifts used to liquidate loan.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Certificate of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1940 (Box 87, Folder 805)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Contribution to National Park Service, 1952-1954 (Box 87, Folder 806)
    Contributions by Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI) used to purchase private land in park area.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Contribution for Rockland Lake Project, 1958 (Box 87, Folder 807)
    Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI) contribution to Palisades Interstate Park Commission.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Contribution to Student Conservation Program, 1958 (Box 87, Folder 808)
    Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI) contribution for work in Grand Teton National Park.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Budget, 1943-1958 (Box 87, Folder 809)
    Discussions of methods of meeting deficits.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 810)
    Audit and financial statement. Content is missing from file as of March 6, 2009.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Conservation Book, 1953-1957 (Box 87, Folder 811)
    Preparation of book on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s conservation activities, "The Heritage of Every American." Selection of author, preparation of manuscript, financing publication, distribution and reception of book. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Kenneth Chorley, Horace Albright.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Conservation Book, 1953-1957 (Box 87, Folder 811A)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Conservation Book, 1956-1961 (Box 87, Folder 812)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Conservation Book, 1956-1961 (Box 87, Folder 0812A)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Property Purchases, 1946-1955 (Box 87, Folder 813)
    Purchases in park area by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as an individual, by Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), and by JHPI matching gifts to U. S. Park Service. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Reports, 1942-1945 (Box 87, Folder 814)
    A. E. Kendrew's 1942 report on condition of buildings; historical background; Harold Fabian's report on progress and prospects, 1945.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Reports, 1942-1945 (Box 88, Folder 815)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Gifts, 1941-1960 (Box 88, Folder 816)
    Gifts to Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI) for purchase of privately owned land in Grand Teton and other parks (South Calaveras Grove, Virgin Islands, Cypress Sanctuary), for construction of lodges, and for general conservation. Totaled approximately $21,000,000 from John D. Rockefeller, Jr., plus $725,000 toward new hospital in Jackson Hole. $4,000,000 from Laurance S. Rockefeller. $2,000,000 from Rockefeller Brothers Fund. 1957 list of family contributions. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Kenneth Chorley, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Gifts, 1941-1960 (Box 88, Folder 817)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park, 1945-1954 (Box 88, Folder 818)
    Cooperation with New York Zoological Society in developing game park in Jackson Hole; criticisms of plan for park; physical problems. Reports on conditions. Park opened in 1948; Laurance S. Rockefeller address at opening. Management problems. Park turned over to Park Service, 1953. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Harold Fabian, Janus Simon, Fairfield Osborn.
    169N1361A
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park, 1945-1954 (Box 88, Folder 819)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park, 1945-1954 (Box 89, Folder 820)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park - Miscellaneous Contributions, 1947-1958 (Box 89, Folder 821)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. stock gift to Wildlife Park.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park - Laurance S. Rockefeller Contributions, 1942-1962 (Box 89, Folder 822)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park - Dissolution, 1952-1953 (Box 89, Folder 823)
    Details on transfer to National Park Service.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park - Minutes of Meetings, 1947-1953 (Box 89, Folder 824)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park - Jackson Hole Biological Research Station, 1950-1957 (Box 89, Folder 825)
    Research program at station; liaison with University of Wyoming.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Wildlife Park - Craighead, 1949-1957 (Box 89, Folder 826)
    Craighead twins employed by Conservation Foundation to conduct research in Jackson Hole area; results of one-year study; publication. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Fairfield Osborn, John Craighead, Frank Craighead.
    Closed material in Folder 826A was opened per MSG 02/16/2005. Material was reintegrated into Folder 826 by DA 10/10/2008.
  - Organizations and Parks - Grand Teton Lodge Company, 1946-1953 (Box 89, Folder 827)
    Originally Grand Teton Lodge and Transportation Company. 1946 report on company operations; recommendations; problems in managing and improving existing facilities; financial data, budgets. 1961 report on expansion requirements at Colter Bay; no material on construction of new lodges. Correspondents include Harold Fabian, Kenneth Chorley, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Conrad Wirth, Vanderbilt Webb, Ray Lillie.
    169N1361B
  - Organizations and Parks - Grand Teton Lodge Company, 1953-1961 (Box 90, Folder 828)
  - Organizations and Parks - Grand Teton Lodge Company - Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 90, Folder 829)
    Formerly Grand Teton Lodge and Transportation Company.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. - Highway Construction, 1946-1949 (Box 90, Folder 830)
    Location and securing of lands for Eastside Highway through Jackson Hole. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley.
    169N1361C
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge, 1950-1955 (Box 90, Folder 831)
    Underwood's 1950 Report on Development of Public Concessions in Park; decision to build entirely new lodge rather than improve existing facilities. Public relations problems; blueprints; plans for Coulter Bay; fact sheet on Lodge. Landscaping; decorating; letters of appreciation to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1956 Study of Jenny Lake Lodge. Correspondents include Harold Fabian, G. S. Underwood, Conrad Wirth, Raymond Lillie, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    169N1361D
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge, 1955-1961 (Box 90, Folder 832)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge - Publicity, 1953-1958 (Box 90, Folder 833)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letter to Laurance S. Rockefeller regarding his feelings about early opposition to Park and public's later change of mind. Copies of clippings and magazine stories on Park.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge - Laurance S. Rockefeller Address, 1955 (Box 90, Folder 834)
    Given at opening of Lodge; copy of draft and final address; Keneth Chorley's remarks; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letter.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge - Applications for Positions, 1953-1960 (Box 90, Folder 835)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge - Opening of Lodge, 1955-1956 (Box 91, Folder 836)
    Public relations plan; letters of appreciation and congratulations; program.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Lodge - Letters of Appreciation, 1954-1960 (Box 91, Folder 837)
  - Organizations and Parks - Caneel Bay Plantation, Inc., 1954-1961 (Box 91, Folder 838)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller contributed stock of Caneel Bay Plantation to Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), 1955. Management of resort; appeals for reservations; comments on operations. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Allston Boyer, Kenneth Chorley.
    169N1361E
  - Organizations and Parks - Caneel Bay Plantation, Inc. - Letters of Appreciation, 1955-1961 (Box 91, Folder 839)
  - Organizations and Parks - Caneel Bay Plantation, Inc. - Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 91, Folder 840)
  - Organizations and Parks - Caneel Bay Plantation, Inc. - Revised Public Relations Plan, 1956 (Box 91, Folder 841)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Property - Transfer to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1942-1946 (Box 91, Folder 842)
    Transfer took place on November 30, 1942. Cost and condition of transferred lands. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    169N1362
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Property - Appraisal of Property - Statement, February 3, 1943 (Box 91, Folder 843)
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Property - 1943 Offer and Controversy, 1942-1945 (Box 91, Folder 844)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. asked Secretary of the Interior Harold L. Ickes to get action regarding Jackson Hole; 1943. Franklin Delano Roosevelt declared area a national monument, thus setting off 7-year battle involving Wyoming pressure groups vs. conservationists, state agencies vs. federal agencies, Congress vs. the Executive branch, Republican Party vs. Democratic Party. Attacks on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; his attitude; his advisors' attempts to overcome opposition. 1949-1950 settlement; land finally given to government, 1949. File contains a great deal of interesting and detailed material on the struggle. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Kenneth Chorley, Horace Albright, Fairfield Osborne, F. Drury, Harold L. Ickes, Secretary of the Interior Julius Albert Krug, Thomas Dewey, Senator O'Mahoney, and a cast of thousands.
    169N1363
    Closed material in Folder 844A was opened per EL 11/03/2004. Material was reintegrated into Folder 844 by DA 10/10/2008.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Property - 1943 Offer and Controversy, 1945-1950 (Box 92, Folder 845)
    Closed material in Folder 845A was opened per MSG 03/23/2007. Material was reintegrated into Folder 845 by DA 10/10/2008.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole Property - 1943 Offer and Controversy - Clippings, 1943-1950 (Box 92, Folder 846)
    Includes copies of various bills presented; clippings from Congressional Record; Westbrook Pegler's analysis, etc.
  - Organizations and Parks - Jackson Hole National Monument - 1949 Gift, 1949-1951 (Box 92, Folder 847)
    Kenneth Chorley's visits to Washington to see if the time was right for land transfer; Laurance S. Rockefeller presented deed to National Park Service. Letters of appreciation; laudatory editorials. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Horace Albright.
  - Organizations and Parks - Grand Teton National Park, 1933-1961 (Box 92, Folder 848)
    Appreciation of Grand Teton Park. Jackson Hole area incorporated into Park, 1950. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest; expansion of tourist facilities. Correspondents include Kenneth Chorley, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    169N1364
  - Organizations and Parks - Grand Teton National Park - Gift of R. Lazy S Property to Government, 1955-1956 (Box 92, Folder 849)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave ranch to government in 1955; carried a 20-year lease to former owner.
  - Organizations and Parks - Grand Teton National Park - Development Outline, 1949 (Box 92, Folder 850)
  - Organizations and Parks - Great Smoky Mountains National Park, 1924-1930 (Box 92, Folder 851)
    Brought to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attention in 1924 by W. P. Davis, interest encouraged by Stephen Mather. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledged $1,000,000, 1927, but pledge cancelled when Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial gave $5,000,000 toward park as memorial to Laura Spelman. Growth of park, appreciation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace Albright, Arno B. Cammerer.
    169N137
  - Organizations and Parks - Great Smoky Mountains National Park, 1931-1959 (Box 93, Folder 852)
    Brought to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attention in 1924 by W. P. Davis, interest encouraged by Stephen Mather. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledged $1,000,000, 1927, but pledge cancelled when Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial gave $5,000,000 toward park as memorial to Laura Spelman. Growth of park, appreciation. Photographs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace Albright, Arno B. Cammerer.
  - Organizations and Parks - Great Smoky Mountains National Park - Pledge, 1927-1928, 1933, 1963 (Box 93, Folder 853)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge later cancelled.
  - Organizations and Parks - Great Smoky Mountains National Park - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Pledge, 1928-1931, 1973 (Box 93, Folder 854)
    Payment of $5,000,000, matching funds by North Carolina and Tennessee.
  - Organizations and Parks - Great Smoky Mountains National Park - Tablet and Dedication, 1935-1950 (Box 93, Folder 855)
    Selection of text; Franklin D. Roosevelt dedicates park; weathering of plaque.
  - Organizations and Parks - Shenandoah National Park, 1927-1936 (Box 93, Folder 856)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $160,000 toward purchase of land for park. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arno B. Cammerer.
    169N138
  - Organizations and Parks - Yosemite National Park, 1928-1929 (Box 93, Folder 857)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. read about lumbering in park area, 1928; asked Arno Cammerer if he could do anything to help. Financed survey of timberland; gave $1,650,000 toward purchase of land in matching government payments; appreciation for gift; progress. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace Albright, Arno B. Cammerer, Arthur Woods.
    169N139
  - Organizations and Parks - Yosemite National Park, 1930-1956 (Box 93, Folder 858)
  - Organizations and Parks - Yosemite National Park - Payments, 1928-1930 (Box 93, Folder 859)
  - Organizations and Parks - Virgin Islands National Park, 1954-1961 (Box 94, Folder 860)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller finances park officials' inspection trip to St. John's Island. Comments on Laurance S. Rockefeller's offer of land for new park; passage of enabling act through Congress. Appreciation. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Conrad Wirth.
    169N140
  - Organizations and Parks - Virgin Islands National Park - Contributions, 1954-1955 (Box 94, Folder 861)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to park.
  - Organizations and Parks - Virgin Islands National Park - Publicity, 1956-1958 (Box 94, Folder 862)
    Newspaper comment on park.
  - Organizations and Parks - National Information Bureau, 1940-1961 (Box 94, Folder 863)
    Successor to National Investigation Bureau. Endorsed and investigated agencies supported by philanthropic contributions. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a sustaining member; Rockefeller Brothers Fund and Davison Fund contributions; contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Nelson A. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    169N2
  - Organizations and Parks - National Information Bureau - Contributions, 1919-1960 (Box 94, Folder 864)
    Annual payments.
  - Organizations and Parks - National Information Bureau - Settlement Study, 1923-1929 (Box 94, Folder 865)
    Gift of $3,000; no report made.
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens, 1895-1958 (Box 94, Folder 866)
    John D. Rockefeller gave toward initial fund-raising program. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution of $500,000 toward endowment, 1925. Most appeals declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    169N21
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens - $500,000 Pledge, 1925-1927 (Box 94, Folder 867)
    On his own initiative, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $500,000 toward endowment.
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1938-1961 (Box 94, Folder 868)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller a life member; declined executive position, 1938 and 1940. Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller contributions, 1938-1961. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1938-1961 (Box 94, Folder 0868A)
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens - David Rockefeller, 1940-1960 (Box 95, Folder 869)
    Contributions by Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller.
    DR material removed to Folder 869A.
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens - David Rockefeller, 1940-1960 (Box 95, Folder 0869A)
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Botanical Gardens - Clippings, 1945-1960 (Box 95, Folder 870)
  - Organizations and Parks - National Municipal League, 1929-1959 (Box 95, Folder 871)
    League stressed democratic citizenship training; promoted city manager idea and proportional representation. Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Davison Fund; John D. Rockefeller 3rd interested in work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.
    169N22
  - Organizations and Parks - National Planning Association, 1944-1957 (Box 95, Folder 872)
    Sought to promote broad view on national affairs; appeals declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    169N23
  - Organizations and Parks - National Planning Association - American Council for the Community, 1949-1951 (Box 95, Folder 873)
  - Organizations and Parks - National Planning Association - American Council for the Community, 1949-1951 (Box 95, Folder 0873A)
    David Rockefeller declined participation.
  - Organizations and Parks - National Planning Association - David Rockefeller, 1949-1957 (Box 95, Folder 874)
    No interest.
  - Organizations and Parks - National Planning Association - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1947-1959 (Box 95, Folder 875)
  - Organizations and Parks - National Planning Association - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1952-1959 (Box 95, Folder 876)
  - Organizations and Parks - National Council for Community Improvement, 1948-1954 (Box 95, Folder 877)
    All appeals declined. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard.
    169N231
  - Organizations and Parks - National Amateur Athletic Federation, 1923-1924 (Box 95, Folder 878)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $5,000 to Federation, 1923. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Raymond B. Fosdick.
    169N24
  - Organizations and Parks - National Association of Manufacturers, 1924-1949 (Box 95, Folder 879)
    Invitations to banquets and to speak declined by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; family showed no interest in association. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    169N25
  - Organizations and Parks - National Trust for Historical Preservation in the United States, 1947-1960 (Box 95, Folder 880)
    Congressionally chartered organization; contributions by Colonial Williamsburg and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    169N26
  - Organizations and Parks - National Historic Monuments, 1934-1940, 1945 (Box 95, Folder 881)
    [169N26]
  - Organizations and Parks - Preservation of Whitehall, 1950-1955 (Box 95, Folder 882)
    Charles Scarlett, a friend of Laurance S. Rockefeller, owned 18th century Maryland mansion, sought help in restoration work. In 1951, Laurance S. Rockefeller gave $12,000 through Maryland Historical Society; work completed in 1955. Photographs. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Keneth Chorley, Charles Scarlett, Jr.
    169N261
  - Organizations and Parks - National Foreign Trade Council, 1931-1961 (Box 96, Folder 883)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined membership in group promoting and protecting American foreign trade and investments. Nelson A. Rockefeller speech on Inter-American affairs and his regular contributions to Council's Latin American section. John D. Rockefeller 3rd attended several dinners. Copy of Milton Eisenhower's Report on U.S.-Latin American relations; "Final Declaration" on foreign trade and aid put out by 40th National Convention. Correspondents include E. P. Thomas, Arthur Jones, Edgar B. Young, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    169N27
  - Organizations and Parks - New York Genealogical and Biographical Society, 1905-1943 (Box 96, Folder 884)
    John D. Rockefeller a life member; contributed $10,000 to building fund, 1913; declined later appeals. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined to accept John D. Rockefeller's life membership when it was offered to him, 1943. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson.
    169N3
  - Organizations and Parks - Smithsonian Institution, 1925-1959 (Box 96, Folder 885)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $10,000 for purchase of insect collection. Purchase of wild flower publication; appeals for aid in publication series declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    169N33
  - Organizations and Parks - Smithsonian Institution - National Gallery of Art, 1917-1926 (Box 96, Folder 886)
  - Organizations and Parks - New-York Historical Society, 1900-1961 (Box 96, Folder 887)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. elected life member, 1901; appeals for aid generally declined. In 1956, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made $25,000 gift to finance history of carriage industry in America. Martha Baird Rockefeller pledged up to $12,000 more for completion of book. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Kenneth Chorley, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
    169N4
  - Organizations and Parks - New-York Historical Society - Spengler Collection, 1924-1937 (Box 96, Folder 888)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave Society $30,000 to purchase collection of newspaper clippings covering World War I.
  - Organizations and Parks - New-York Historical Society - Dr. Joseph Broadman Correspondence, 1931-1956 (Box 96, Folder 889)